<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dataroot xmlns:od="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:officedata" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"  xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="HEC_Lists.xsd" generated="2011-04-01T09:21:40">
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>1</ListDBID>
<ListID>goes_sxr_flare</ListID>
<OldListID>goes_xray_flare</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>GOES Soft X-ray Flare List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of X-ray flares based on observations by the GOES spacecraft</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>List generated by NOAA-SWPC based on observations in 0.1-0.8 nm from the XRS instrument on the GOES spacecraft. 

There are usually two GOES spacecraft operational resulting in virtually complete coverage since the 1970s. Recent segments of the catalogue can be found through the NOAA site; archive segments held by the NGDC.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1975-09-01T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2010-12-31T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Selection criteria used by NOAA-SWPC does not properly represent the duration of the flare; revised start and end time have been included (ntime_start and ntime_end). 
Should we list refined times as time_start and time_end - other lists use the time_start define by NOAA ???? 
Comparing the X-ray class for flares greater than X9.9 will fail. 
Locations of the flares are sparsely defined in this list.

Suggest the removal of ntime fields as these are not consistent across all the lists. This capability will be provided within the interface.</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>ftp://ftp.ngdc.noaa.gov/STP/SOLAR_DATA/SOLAR_FLARES/FLARES_XRAY#ftp://ftp.ngdc.noaa.gov/STP/SOLAR_DATA/SOLAR_FLARES/FLARES_XRAY#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>2</ListDBID>
<ListID>ngdc_halpha_flare</ListID>
<OldListID>halpha_flares_events</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>NGDC H-alpha Flare List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of H-alpha flares assembled from ground-based observatories (NGDC)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>Flares are characterized by a rise time of the order of minutes and a decay of the order of tens of minutes. The total energy released in a typical flare is about 10^27 J; the magnetic field is extraordinarily intense, reaching values of 10^-2 to 1 Tesla. 

This list is constructed by NGDC from the basic reports sent monthly from the ground-based observatories. The National Geophysical Data Center (NGDC) holds archives for about 80 stations, covering the period 1938 to the present. Currently 5 stations send their data to NGDC Boulder on a routine monthly basis. Optical flares in H-alpha are usually accompanied by radio and X-ray bursts, and occasionally by high-energy particle emissions.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1980-01-01T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2010-01-31T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>3</ListDBID>
<ListID>noaa_energetic_event</ListID>
<OldListID>sgas_event</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>NOAA Solar Energetic Event List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of energetic solar events, plus radio observations assembled from the daily Solar and Geophysical Activity Summary (SGAS) reports (NOAA)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>A list of significant solar events including start, maximum, and end times, region number and location, X-ray and optical classification of flares, significant radio emission at 245 MHz, 2695 MHz (11 cm), and sweep frequencies, and significant short wave fades. All available data for an event are if one or more of the following thresholds are reached:

        Class-M or greater X-ray flare,
        Optical flare of importance &gt; 2B,
        Radio burst of &gt; 100 sfu at 245 MHz,
        Radio burst  &gt; 100% above background at 2695 MHz,
        Type II or IV sweep frequency burst,
        Shortwave fade of importance 2 or greater.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1996-01-04T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2010-12-31T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>4</ListDBID>
<ListID>soho_lasco_cme</ListID>
<OldListID>lasco_cme_cat</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>SOHO/LASCO CME Event List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>Edited list of CMEs detected by the LASCO instrument on SOHO (NASA/GSFC)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>This CME catalog is generated and maintained at the CDAW Data Center by NASA and The Catholic University of America in cooperation with the Naval Research Laboratory. SOHO is a project of international cooperation between ESA and NASA.

This catalog contains all CMEs manually identified since 1996 from the Large Angle and Spectrometric Coronagraph (LASCO) on board the Solar and Heliospheric Observatory (SOHO) mission. LASCO has three telescopes C1, C2, and C3. However, only C2 and C3 data are used for uniformity because C1 was disabled in June 1998.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1996-01-11T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2010-07-31T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListCaveats>The list is necessarily incomplete because of the nature of identification. In the absence of a perfect automatic CME detector program, the manual identification is still the best way to identify CMEs.

Link to the list of data gaps during the month is also provided. Data gaps of duration 3 h or more are listed. The data-gap list must be consulted before deciding the existence or nonexistence of CMEs. If there is a data gap, it is difficult to say there was a CME or not during the data gap.</ListCaveats>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListRefURL>#http://cdaw.gsfc.nasa.gov/publications/gopal2008.catalog.pdf#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>5</ListDBID>
<ListID>stereo_hi_cme</ListID>
<OldListID>hi_cme_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>STEREO Heliospheric Imager CME Event List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of CME events identified using the STEREO heliospheric imager instrument (RALspace)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>This list was compiled by Richard Harrison (RALspace) through careful inspection of the images obtained from the STEREO HI cameras. As such it is a more detailed list of CMEs, linking each to the appropriate transients seen in the &quot;stereo_hi_sw_transient&quot;  where possible. The list contains information about direction and extent of each CME in terms of solar position angle. 

Since the  process of visual identification of CMEs is time-consuming, this list is currently only complete for CMEs occurring to the end of 2008.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>2007-03-31T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2008-12-27T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListCaveats>The &quot;time_start&quot; and &quot;time_end&quot; correspond to the times that the CME was seen to enter and leave (or fade) from the STEREO HI field of view.

Since STEREO A (Ahead) and B (Behind) are in heliocentric orbits their view angle with respect to the Sun-Earth line varies with time from the start of the mission.</ListCaveats>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.sstd.rl.ac.uk/stereo/Events%20Page.html#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>6</ListDBID>
<ListID>goes_proton_event</ListID>
<OldListID>noaa_proton_event</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>GOES Proton Event List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>Geo-effective solar energetic proton (SEP) events (NOAA)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>Proton fluxes are integral 5-minute averages for energies &gt;10 MeV, given in Particle Flux Units (pfu), measured by GOES spacecraft at Geosynchronous orbit: 1 pfu = 1 p cm^-2 sr^-1 s^-1. 

The start of a proton event is identified based on the first of 3 consecutive data points with fluxes greater than or equal to 10 pfu. The end of an event is the last time the flux was greater than or equal to 10 pfu. It should be recognised that this definition allows multiple proton flares and/or interplanetary
shock proton increases to occur within one SWO proton event. Additional data may be necessary to more completely resolve any individual proton event.

Flare associations are given, although data about individual Coronal Mass Ejections (CMEs), available from SOHO since 1996 only, are necessary to fully characterize each event. CME information for earlier events from the SOLWIND and SMM coronagraphs will be added in the future.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1976-04-30T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2006-12-13T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListCaveats>Different detectors, onboard different GOES spacecraft, have taken the data since 1976. These proton data were processed using various algorithms. To date, no attempt has been made to cross-normalize the resulting proton fluxes.</ListCaveats>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Needs to be regenerated (ESA has two contracts out to do this).

Changed List ID from &apos;noaa_proton_event&apos; to &apos;goes_proton_event&apos;.

Changed List Name to GOES proton events.</ListProdNotes>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>7</ListDBID>
<ListID>bas_magnetic_storms</ListID>
<OldListID>bas_magnetic_storms</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>BAS Magnetic Storms</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of geo-effective magnetic storms (Contibuted by R Horne, BAS)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>This list has been contributed by R Horne from the British Antarctic Survey. Storms are identified as a variation in the terrestrial ring current characterised by an excursion of Dst below -20nT with a minimum below -50nT.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1992-01-08T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2002-12-28T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListProdNotes>Could this be updated either from Richard or automatically from MDES?</ListProdNotes>
<ListContact>R Horne, BAS</ListContact>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.antarctica.ac.uk/SatelliteRisks#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>8</ListDBID>
<ListID>aad_gle</ListID>
<OldListID>gle_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>AAD Ground Level Enhancement List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of ground level events detected by ground-based neutron monitors</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>Ground level enhancements (GLEs) are sudden increases in the cosmic ray intensity recorded by ground based detectors. GLEs are invariably associated with large solar flares but the acceleration mechanism producing particles of up to tens of GeV is not understood. The increases in ground based measurements ranges from only a few percent of background in polar monitors (with little or no geomagnetic cutoff) to 45 times for the 23 February 1956 event. The rate of GLEs would appear to be about one per year but there may be a slight clumping around solar maximum.

Most solar flares associated with GLEs are located on the western sector of the Sun where the Interplanetary Magnetic Field (IMF) is well connected to the Earth. The geometry of this field line is quite variable, as it depends on the strength of the solar wind that varies considerably. Because of its shape it is known as the ``garden hose&apos;&apos; field line. 

GLEs associated with flares located near to the footpoint of the garden hose field line usually arrive promptly and have very sharp onsets. Conversely, GLEs associated with flares far from the garden hose field line are usually delayed in their arrival at Earth and have more gradual increases to maximum intensity. It is very rare to observe GLEs associated with flares to the east of the central meridian or Sun-Earth line. Although a large solar flare is invariably associated with a GLE the flare itself may not be causally related to the production of the high energy protons that produce the GLE response at Earth. Solar energetic particle events are not rare and energetic protons are produced in common with CMEs and interplanetary shocks. These protons do not have sufficient energy to produce secondary particles that reach ground level but are clearly observed by spacecraft. Such CMEs and their associated shocks are most often produced without a solar flare. It is possible that there is a continuum to the acceleration process and that flares are a by-product of the most energetic events. Alternatively, there is a possibility that the flare itself produces a seed population of higher energy protons that are further accelerated to energies sufficient to produce a GLE.
(Ref: http://www.atnf.csiro.au/pasa/18_1/duldig/paper/node6.html)</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1942-02-28T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2006-12-13T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>The formal GLE event number is missing from the catalogue and should be added.</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://neutronm.bartol.udel.edu/~pyle/GLE_List.txt#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>9</ListDBID>
<ListID>ngdc_aastar_storm</ListID>
<OldListID>aastar_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>NGDC AA* Major Magnetic Storm List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of major magnetic storms according to the AA* criteria (NGDC)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>Daily regular magnetic field variation arise from current systems caused by regular solar radiation changes. Other irregular current systems produce magnetic field changes caused by the interaction of the solar wind with the magnetosphere, by the magnetosphere itself, by the interactions between the magnetosphere and ionosphere, and by the ionosphere itself.

Magnetic activity indices were designed to describe variation in the geomagnetic field caused by these irregular current systems

The aa-index is a simple global geomagnetic activity index. It is derived from the K indices from two approximately antipodal observatories and has units of 1 nT. The K-index is quasi-logarithmic local index of the 3-hourly range in magnetic activity relative to an assumed quiet-day curve for a single geomagnetic observatory site. First introduced by J. Bartels in 1938, it consists of a single-digit 0 thru 9 for each 3-hour interval of the universal time day (UT).

This list has been produced at WDC-A for STP, a now-routine procedure is to take the 3-hourly aa indices when they are received and compute an 8-point running average.  When this mean exceeds 60, a &quot;major magnetic&quot; storm is considered to be in progress.  It is arbitrarily considered to continue in progress until such time as the value drops below a threshold of 60.  Then the maximum mean value attained
is designated AA*.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1868-03-20T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2008-03-27T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>10</ListDBID>
<ListID>ngdc_apstar_storm</ListID>
<OldListID>apstar_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>NGDC Ap* Major Magnetic Storm List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of major magnetic storms according to the Ap* criteria (NGDC)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>Daily regular magnetic field variation arise from current systems caused by regular solar radiation changes. Other irregular current systems produce magnetic field changes caused by the interaction of the solar wind with the magnetosphere, by the magnetosphere itself, by the interactions between the magnetosphere and ionosphere, and by the ionosphere itself.

Magnetic activity indices were designed to describe variation in the geomagnetic field caused by these irregular current systems.

The 3-hourly ap (equivalent range) index is derived from the Kp index. The planetary 3-hour-range index Kp is the mean standardized K-index from 13 geomagnetic observatories between 44 degrees and 60 degrees northern or southern geomagnetic latitude - for the conversion from Kp to ap, see http://www.ngdc.noaa.gov/stp/geomag/kp_ap.html.

The Ap* index is defined as the earliest occurring maximum 24-hour value obtained by computing an 8-point running average of successive 3-hour ap indices during a geomagnetic storm event and is uniquely associated with the storm event. At WDC-A for STP, a now-routine procedure is to take the 3-hourly ap indices when they are received and compute the 8-point running average.  When this mean exceeds 40, a &quot;major magnetic storm&quot; is considered to be in progress. It is arbitrarily considered to continue in progress until such time as the value drops below a threshold of 40.  Then the maximum mean value attained is designated Ap*. When the most disturbed 24-hours begin at the start of the UT-day, the values of Ap and Ap* are identical.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1932-03-10T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2006-12-16T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.ngdc.noaa.gov/stp/GEOMAG/apstar.html#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>11</ListDBID>
<ListID>ngdc_ssc</ListID>
<OldListID>ssc_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>NGDC Storm Sudden Commencement List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of the onset of geo-magnetic storms (NGDC)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>SEC defines geomagnetic storms based on the running Boulder A-index. If the index is greater than or equal to 30, a storm is in progress. The running A-index is calculated using the K indices in a running 24-hour window, rather than using fixed days. Storms are minor, major, or severe as defined below. 
     minor: A+B between 30 and 49 
     major: A+B between 50 and 99 
     severe: A+B 100 or greater</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1968-01-02T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2006-11-09T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListCaveats>However, the level of storm conditions can vary throughout a day. Regardless of the running A-index, it is permissible to say that periods at minor, major, or severe storm levels occurred, based on the observed K index. The following table identifies K indices with storm levels. 
     minor storm conditions: K=5 
     major storm conditions: K=6 
     severe storm conditions: K=7 or greater</ListCaveats>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListRefURL>#ftp://ftp.ngdc.noaa.gov/STP/SOLAR_DATA/SUDDEN_COMMENCEMENTS/storm2#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>12</ListDBID>
<ListID>cme_forbush_event</ListID>
<OldListID>forbush_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>CME-related Forbush Decrease Event List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of Forbush decreases related to CMEs (Contributed by E Eroshenko, Izmiran)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The magnetic field configurations propagating through the Heliosphere as Interplanetary Coronal Mass Ejections (ICMEs) also reduce the galactic cosmic ray flux. The count rates before an event are subtracted, and the rates given as a percentage of the count rate as compared to the average values measured before the event. The depressions can attain values of 20%. They are called Forbush decreases after the cosmic ray physicist Scott Forbush. The depressions of cosmic ray flux are ascribed to the shield produced by the complex and turbulent magnetic field structure in and around the ICME and the shock wave it drives ahead of it.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1957-08-29T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2006-12-14T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListCaveats>All data are for Cosmic Rays of 10GV rigidity.</ListCaveats>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Cannot find any documentation to explain fields.</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.nmdb.eu/?q=node/135#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>13</ListDBID>
<ListID>solar_wind_event</ListID>
<OldListID>solar_wind_event</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>Solar wind events</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of solar wind events observed upstream of the Earth</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The ISTP Science Planning and Operations Facility (SPOF), in collaboration with ISTP investigators, is developing this catalog of preliminary/selected solar wind events and features. The catalog also contains listings of times when WIND and IMP-8 were in the solar wind. Coverage begins on September 8, 1992, the start of ISTP science data collection. With the launch of ACE in 1997, and its permanent coverage of solar wind conditions in near real time we incorporate to our selection interesting time periods also observed with the instruments SWEPAM and MAG in ACE.

The solar wind features are classified into several categories (e.g., interplanetary shock wave, extended period of strong negative Bz, etc.). An extended event has separate start and end times listed for it, whereas a sharp discontinuous event (such as a shock ramp) has the same time listed for both start and end times (clearly, for follow-up studies researchers will need to examine data before and after the listed time).</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1986-07-12T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2000-11-27T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListCaveats>The catalog contains information on selected features of the solar wind at 1 AU whose signatures derive from plasma and magnetic field measurements from the IMP-8 and WIND spacecraft in the form of Key Parameters (KPs -- preliminary summary data at ~1 min time resolution produced quickly for survey purposes); as such, the catalog should not be used a definitive source in formal scientific work.

Researchers using the catalog should reference its contents with statements such as: The event from &quot;Feb 26, 1995&quot; has been identified as a candidate &quot;Sector Boundary Crossing&quot; worthy of further study. The primary intent for the catalog is to serve as a reference for identifying candidate periods for further study, such as may be the focus of coordinated data analysis efforts during ISTP and/or IACG Science Campaigns.

The list should not be considered as comprehensive.</ListCaveats>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>This is the same as the istp_solar_wind_event list but formatted in a different way. Need to decide which to keep. Bob prefers to have the values in a single field rather than separate flags for each type of feature.</ListProdNotes>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>14</ListDBID>
<ListID>yohkoh_hxr_flare</ListID>
<OldListID>yohkoh_flare_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>Yohkoh/HXT Hard X-ray Flare List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>Flare list from the Yohkoh Hard X-ray Telescope</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>This list contains all solar flares recorded with Yohkoh HXT during the interval be-
tween October 1, 1991 and December 14, 2001.

The HXT is a hard X-ray imager of the Fourier-synthesis type, consisting of 64 mod-
ulation subcollimators. Each modulation subcollimator is equipped with a small NaI(Tl)
scintillator and photomultiplier tube, and measures a modulated photon count. A set of
the 64 photon counts, transmitted from the satellite to the ground, is converted into an
image by image synthesis procedures. The main characteristics of HXT are summarized
below:
i) Simultaneous imaging in four energy bands, namely, the L-band (13.9 - 22.7 keV),
M1-band (22.7 - 32.7 keV), M2-band (32.7 - 52.7 keV), and H-band (52.7 - 92.8 keV).
Ii) Angular resolution of about 5 arcsec with a wide field of view covering the whole Sun.
Iii) Basic temporal resolution of 0.5 s.
Iv) High sensitivity with an effective area of about 60 cm^2.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1991-10-01T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2001-12-14T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListCaveats>Note that due to orbit there is not 24 hour coverage.

In the Yohkoh operation, the observation mode is automatically controlled by the
onboard Data Processor, and intense flares trigger the so-called Flare mode. Weak flares,
however, are recorded in the Quiet mode without triggering the Flare mode. Since only
the L-band count rate is recorded in the Quiet mode, flares sometimes lack the M1-, M2-,
and H-band count rates.</ListCaveats>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>the Sato paper provides the detailed reference and link to the source. Need to check that this list is indeed the same as the one in the sato.

Add long_carr.</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://gedas22.stelab.nagoya-u.ac.jp/HXT/catalogue/image_html/all_images.html#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>15</ListDBID>
<ListID>rhessi_hxr_flare</ListID>
<OldListID>hessi_flare</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>RHESSI Hard X-ray Flare List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of hard X-ray flares seen by RHESSI.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The RHESSI flare list is created during quicklook processing (and is often re-processed). 

The flare list is obtained by comparing the observing summary count rate in the 6 to 12 keV energy band to a threshold. The count rate threshold is determined from the background level; which is obtained using a 60 second running average. For an interval to be considered as a flare candidate, the count rate must be greater than 3*sigma above the background level. Variations in the count rate due to changes in attenuator state or decimation state are taken into account by use of the &quot;corrected&quot; count rate method, which empirically determines the corrections. 

A flare candidate is flagged as a possible solar flare if the ratio of the count rate in the front detectors to total count rate is 3 sigma above its own background level (also determined using a 60 second running average). An exception is made if there is an SAA crossing or data gap; for those cases the front - total ratio must be greater than 60% in the interval for that interval to be considered to be a possible flare. 

Even with the front - total ratio test, particle precipitation events can be confused with flares. The candidate is only confirmed as a solar flare if a valid position is found in the 6 to 12 keV energy band.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>2002-02-12T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2011-01-17T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListRefURL>#http://hesperia.gsfc.nasa.gov/ssw/hessi/dbase/#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>16</ListDBID>
<ListID>kso_halpha_flare</ListID>
<OldListID>kso_flare</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>Kanzelhoehe Solar Observatory (KSO) H-alpha Flare List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>Flares observed in H-alpha by the Kanzelhoehe Observatory.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The list contains the following information for each flare:

   observed beginning of the flare 
   observed maximum of the flare 
   observed end of the flare
   heliographic position of the flare 
   Type: area (importance) [S, 1, 2, 3] and brightness [F, N, B] of the flare</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1984-01-02T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2010-11-15T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.kso.ac.at/beobachtungen/sonne_daten/flares_en.php#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>17</ListDBID>
<ListID>soho_eit_wave_transient</ListID>
<OldListID>eit_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>SOHO/EIT Wave Transient List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>Waves seen in the EUV by SOHO/EIT.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>Abstract taken from &apos;A CATALOG OF CORONAL &quot;EIT WAVE&quot; TRANSIENTS&apos; by B. J. Thompson and D. C. Myers, The Astrophysical Journal Supplement Series 183 (2009) 225.

Solar and Heliospheric Observatory (SOHO) Extreme ultraviolet Imaging Telescope (EIT) data have been visually searched for coronal &quot;EIT wave&quot; transients over the period beginning from 1997 March 24 and extending through 1998 June 24. The dates covered start at the beginning of regular high-cadence (more than 1 image every 20 minutes) observations, ending at the four-month interruption of SOHO observations in mid-1998. One hundred and seventy six events are included in this catalog. The observations range from &quot;candidate&quot; events, which were either weak or had insufficient data coverage, to events which were well defined and were clearly distinguishable in the data. Included in the catalog are times of the EIT images in which the events are observed, diagrams indicating the observed locations of the wave fronts and associated active regions, and the speeds of the wave fronts. The measured speeds of the wave fronts varied from less than 50 to over 700 km s^–1 with &quot;typical&quot; speeds of 200-400 km s^–1.

URL for paper: http://iopscience.iop.org/0067-0049/183/2/225/apjs_183_2_225.text.html</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1997-03-25T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>1998-06-16T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>This list only covers a short interval…could it be replaced or suplemented by NEMO.

Renamed List ID &apos;eit_list&apos;  to &apos;eit_waves_list&apos;.

Changed List Name to &apos;EIT waves list&apos;.</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://iopscience.iop.org/0067-0049/183/2/225/apjs300645t3.html#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>18</ListDBID>
<ListID>yohkoh_sxt_trace_list</ListID>
<OldListID>yohkoh_sxt_trace_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>YOHKOH SXT TRACE flare list</ListName>
<ListPurpose>Common flares observed by Yohkoh/SXT and TRACE.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>This list is compiled from the Yohkoh flare directories at ISAS as maintained by Mr. Sawa and the online TRACE catalog generated by SSW. In the following table, click a line under &apos;SXT PFI file&apos; (leftmost column) for a plot of GOES/HXT light curves and SXT/TRACE data coverage.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1900-01-22T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>1999-12-27T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>The list start date looks to have a typing error as 1900 is well before the start of Yohkoh operations.

Do we want to remove this because it only covers a short time interval.

Disable for now.</ListProdNotes>
<ListContact>Contact N. V. Nitta &lt;nitta@lmsal.com&gt; if you have questions/comments.</ListContact>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.lmsal.com/nitta/sxt_trace_flares/list.html#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>19</ListDBID>
<ListID>lasco_cme_list</ListID>
<OldListID>lasco_cme_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>SOHO LASCO preliminary CME list</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of CMEs detected by SOHO/LASCO built from Alerts (SOHO/GSFC)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>This is a working version of a catalogue of activity and probable  coronal mass ejections detected in white light observations of the LASCO coronagraphs.  This list is maintained at the SOHO Experimenters&apos; Operations Facility, and it is based on an examination of only quick-look data, which represents a subset of the final LASCO dataset. Questions about this list should be directed to: lascoplanner@grace.nascom.nasa.gov .</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1900-05-26T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2009-12-23T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListCaveats>
Bob would like to remove this list it is difficult to handle and is partly duplicated by lasco_cme_cat</ListCaveats>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>The list start date looks to have a typing error as 1900 is well before the start of SOHO operations.

Consider removing this list.</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#ftp://lasco6.nascom.nasa.gov/pub/lasco/status#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>20</ListDBID>
<ListID>stereo_hi_sw_transient</ListID>
<OldListID>hi_event</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>STEREO/HI Solar Wind Transient List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of STEREO/HI solar wind transient events</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>This list contains speeds and directions calculated from time-height &apos;j-plots&apos; along the ecliptic for all solar wind transients that are seen to propagate into the outer H12 cameras field of view. As this list is derived semi-automatically it contains speeds and directions for both coronal mass ejections (CMEs) and co-rotating interaction (CIRs) and does not distinguish between them.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>2007-03-25T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2010-05-26T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Rename the list to make it clearer - &apos;stereo_hi_event&apos; instead of &apos;hi_event&apos;.

The description of date and time_start should make it clearer what they refer to.

See section 3 of http://www.sstd.rl.ac.uk/Stereo/Documents/HI_user_guidejuly.pdf.</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.sstd.rl.ac.uk/Stereo/HIEventList.html#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>21</ListDBID>
<ListID>wind_mfi_mag_cloud</ListID>
<OldListID>wind_imf_mag_cloud</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>WIND/MFI Magnetic Cloud List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of Magnetic Cloud events observed by the WIND MFI instrument.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>A magnetic cloud is a transient ejection in the solar wind defined by relatively strong magnetic fields, a large and smooth rotation of the magnetic field direction over approximately 0.25AU at 1AU, and a low proton temperature [Burlaga et al., 1981]. Magnetic clouds are ideal objects for solar-terrestrial studies because of their simplicity and their extended intervals of southward and northward magnetic fields [Burlaga et al., 1990]

The table consists of estimated start and end times that were estimated by a magnetic field model [Lepping et al., 1990] that assumes that the field within the magnetic cloud is force free, i.e., so that the electrical current and the magnetic field are parallel and proportional in strength everywhere within its volume.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1995-02-08T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2007-11-20T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Initial version had incorrect acronym for the instrument - IMF instead of MFI. List ID, List Name and Purpose have been corrected accordingly.</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://wind.nasa.gov/mfi/mag_cloud_pub1.html#table#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>22</ListDBID>
<ListID>wind_mfi_bs_crossing_time</ListID>
<OldListID>wind_imf_bow_shock</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>WIND/MFI Bow Shock Cross Crossing Time List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of WIND MFI Bow Shock crossing times</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The Bow Shock is the shock wave observed just upstream of the Earth&apos;s magnetosphere caused by the supersonic and super-Alfvenic solar wind ramming into the Earth&apos;s magnetosphere. (SuperAlfvenic refers to when the solar wind&apos;s speed exceeds a characteristic speed that depends on the solar wind&apos;s density and the interplanetary magnetic field strength.) The MFI team has provided a list of all WIND bow shock crossings. 

The event list provides a list of bow shock (BS) crossing times. For each crossing, the following times are given:

    The time of the last BS crossing as the spacecraft was leaving the Earth magnetosheath. 
    The first full hour which has only unshocked solar wind data in it.
    The last full hour which still contains interplanetary magnetic field data.
    The time of the 1st BS crossing on the way into the Earth magnetosphere.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1994-11-12T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2003-10-13T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Location</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>The URL used to obtain these data is no longer available.

Need to update this description as it is a bit unclear.

Initial version had incorrect acronym for the instrument - IMF instead of MFI. List ID, List Name and Purpose have been corrected accordingly.

Additional information added to descripyion</ListProdNotes>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>23</ListDBID>
<ListID>istp_sw_event</ListID>
<OldListID>istp_solar_wind_cat</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>ISTP Solar Wind Candidate Event List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>ISTP solar wind catalogue candidate events.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The events in the list corerespond to one or more of several features observed by the IMP-8, WIND and ACE spacecraft. These features include:

BzN  - Interplanetary magnetic B-field North (GSM coordinate system)
BzS - Interplanetary magnetic B-field South (GSM coordinate system)
EyC - Change of the &quot;y&quot; component of the Interplanetary Electric Field
HSS - High Speed Stream
IMC - Interplanetary Magnetic Cloud
IR - Interaction Region
IS - Interplanetary Fast Shock
LSS - Low Speed Stream
PC - Pressure Change
SBC - Sector Boundaries Crossing, also heliospheric current sheet crossing
MISC - Miscellaneous Events</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1986-07-01T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2007-09-07T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Move the description of the category into the field description


Moved full description of features to field description.</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://www-spof.gsfc.nasa.gov/scripts/sw-cat/Catalog_events.html#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>24</ListDBID>
<ListID>soho_pm_ip_shock</ListID>
<OldListID>soho_pm_ips</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>SOHO/CELIAS/MTOF/PM Interplanetary Shock List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>An incomplete list of possible Interplanetary Shocks observed by the SOHO PM.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The Shockspotter program attempts to identify possible interplanetary shocks using the near-real time data from the CELIAS/MTOF/PM sensor on the SOHO spacecraft. 

There are several reasons for developing automated procedures for identifying various interplanetary structures; for example the online capability of such techniques would be a useful addition to a space weather warning system, and could be used by spacecraft to make on-board decisions to change modes of operation. In addition, the objectivity of such an automated identification system is a benefit for unbiased statistical analyses.

Rigorously, shocks cannot be identified using solely solar wind proton data; one needs electron and minor ion measurements in addition to magnetic field measurements (there is no magnetometer on SOHO). Nevertheless, a reasonable system of identification of at least the larger shocks is possible using only the PM data.

This simplified Table lists the expected behavior of solar wind parameters across some common interplanetary structures: 

                                              Vsw                 Np                   Vth             B 
          
fast FWD shock             increases    increases      increases      increases 
fast REV shock               increases    decreases     decreases    decreases 
          
slow FWD shock           increases     increases      increases     decreases 
slow REV shock             increases    decreases     decreases    increases 
          
classical CME TD/CD        steady      decreases     decreases    increases 
          
classical high-speed    increases   decreases     increases     decreases
stream</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1996-09-26T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2010-08-03T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Move the field descriptions into the field.

There is also the archival history file which uses  the final science data files. Should this be used as well?</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://umtof.umd.edu/pm/FIGS.html#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>25</ListDBID>
<ListID>wind_mfi_ip_shock</ListID>
<OldListID>wind_imf_ips</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>WIND/MFI Interplanetary Shock List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of Interplanetary Shocks identified by the WIND MFI instrument.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>This list contains the times of interplanetary shocks identified by the WIND MFI instrument. (Note that there was provision for the type of shock and driver in the list, but these fields have no data so the list only contains times.)</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1994-12-05T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>1998-06-25T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Location</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>The URL used to obtain these data is no longer available.

Initial version had incorrect acronym for the instrument - IMF instead of MFI. List ID, List Name and Purpose have been corrected accordingly.</ListProdNotes>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>26</ListDBID>
<ListID>wind_sw_crossing_time</ListID>
<OldListID>wind_solar_wind_times</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>WIND Solar Wind Crossing Time List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>WIND Solar Wind Times.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>Times when WIND was in the Solar Wind, as identified from the Key Parameter data. It must be noted that actual entry/exit times may be different due to data gaps preventing identification.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1994-11-16T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2001-02-19T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Location</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Consider moving to the ILS</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>http://www-spof.gsfc.nasa.gov/scripts/sw-cat/Catalog_SWtimes.html#http://www-spof.gsfc.nasa.gov/scripts/sw-cat/Catalog_SWtimes.html#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>27</ListDBID>
<ListID>imp8_sw_crossing_time</ListID>
<OldListID>imp8_solar_wind_times</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>IMP-8 Solar Wind Crossing Time List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>IMP-8 Solar Wind Times.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>Times when IMP-8 was in the Solar Wind, as identified from the Key Parameter data. It must be noted that actual entry/exit times may be different due to data gaps preventing identification.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1993-01-30T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>1996-07-18T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Location</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Consider moving to the ILS</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>http://www-spof.gsfc.nasa.gov/scripts/sw-cat/Catalog_SWtimes.html#http://www-spof.gsfc.nasa.gov/scripts/sw-cat/Catalog_SWtimes.html#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>28</ListDBID>
<ListID>tsrs_solar_radio_event</ListID>
<OldListID>tsrs_event_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>Trieste Solar Radio System (TSRS) Solar Radio Event List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>Trieste Solar Radio System decimetric event list</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>Solar radio bursts at 1420 and 2695 MHz with flux density greater than 400 sfu (solar flux
unit) have been analysed in order to characterise them in time, peak flux density, dominant circular polarization sense, and morphological class. The list contains events from 2000 to 2006. The morphological classification has been carried out based on the specifications illustrated in Solar-Geophysical Data, Explanation of data reports (July 1987, No. 515).</ListDesc>
<ListStart>2000-07-12T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2006-12-05T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Could not find documentation for fields cpp, ps and radio_class

Get information from INAF

Updated with information from INAF.</ListProdNotes>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>29</ListDBID>
<ListID>latest_gev_flare</ListID>
<OldListID>latest_gev_flare</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>Latest GEV flare</ListName>
<ListPurpose>Latest GEV flare list.</ListPurpose>
<ListStart>2010-10-13T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2010-11-28T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>URL points to latest events over the past month - there is no description.

Bob suggests to remove this list or update, the information could be in or added to the goes_event_list</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.mssl.ucl.ac.uk/~rdb/egso-sec/latest_gev.txt#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>30</ListDBID>
<ListID>gevloc_flares</ListID>
<OldListID>gevloc_flares</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>GEV flare location</ListName>
<ListPurpose>Flares positions returned by GEVLOC (LMSAL)</ListPurpose>
<ListStart>2010-11-16T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2010-11-29T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Location</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>The URL points to the most recent events - is there an archive for these events?

Bob suggests to remove this list since it does not add much to other lists</ListProdNotes>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>31</ListDBID>
<ListID>wind_typeii_soho_cme</ListID>
<OldListID>wind_waves_type_ii_burst</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>Type II Radio Burst (WIND) and Associated CME (SOHO) List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of  Radio-loud CMEs observed by the Wind/WAVES experiment</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>This is a catalog of type II bursts observed by the Radio and Plasma Wave (WAVES) experiment on board the Wind spacecraft and the associated coronal mass ejections (CMEs) observed by the Solar and Heliospheric Observatory (SOHO) mission. The type II burst catalog is derived from the Wind/WAVES catalog available at http://lep694.gsfc.nasa.gov/waves/waves.html by adding a few missing events. 

The CMEs in this catalog are called radio-loud CMEs because of their ability to produce type II radio bursts. The CME sources are also listed, as derived from the Solar Geophysical Data listing or from inner coronal images such as Yohkoh/SXT and SOHO/EIT. Some solar sources have also been obtained from Solarsoft Latest Events Archive after October 1, 2002: http://www.lmsal.com/solarsoft/latest_events_archive.html</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1997-04-01T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2008-04-26T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Consider renaming this…is it radio loud CMEs

Renamed List ID from  to &apos;wind_waves_type_ii_burst&apos; to &apos;radio_loud_cmes&apos;.
Renamed List Name to &apos;Radio-loud CMEs&apos;.</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://cdaw.gsfc.nasa.gov/CME_list/radio/waves_type2.html#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>32</ListDBID>
<ListID>wind_stereo_ii_iv_radioburst</ListID>
<OldListID>waves_exp_wind_stereo</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>WIND and STEREO Candidate Type II and IV Radio Burst List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>WAVES Experiment on WIND and STEREO - Type II/IV List</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>This is a listing year-by-year of POSSIBLE solar type II and type IV bursts detected by the WAVES instruments on the Wind and STEREO spacecraft. Each table entry consists of a start and stop time and an upper and lower frequency limit. The four items form a box on the dynamic spectrum which contains the bursts. It is not always the case that the highest (lowest) frequency happens at the earliest (latest) time. Also included in most entries are comments and a dynamic spectrum of at least part of the emission. The dynamic spectra come in two flavors: those marked with &apos;S&apos; or &apos;X&apos; are standard frequency versus time dynamic spectra. Those marked with &apos;F&apos; are inverse frequency versus time, corresponding roughly to distance from the sun versus time.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1994-12-23T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2009-05-05T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>note that it is not possible to tell which spacecraft the observation comes from…what do we do about this?</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://lep694.gsfc.nasa.gov/waves/#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>33</ListDBID>
<ListID>ulysses_swoops_icme</ListID>
<OldListID>ulysses_swoops_icme</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>Ulysses/SWOOPS Interplanetary CME List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of CMEs observed by the SWOOPS particle instrument on Ulysses.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The Ulysses ICME list for the period from February 18, 1992 through April 5, 2008. The events from 1992 through 2002 were obtained directly from the Ulysses ICME list (http://swoops.lanl.gov/cme_list.html). The events from the start of 2003 onward were identified by Ebert et al (J. Geophys. Res., 114, 2009).

The identification of ICMEs from in-situ solar wind measurements is not a straightforward process [Gosling, 1996; Zurbuchen and Richardson, 2006]. There is no single feature exhibited by all ICMEs and no standard signature that can be used to identify them all. A combination of signatures was used to find ICMEs in the SWOOPS and MAG data. These signatures include bi-directional electrons [Montgomery et al., 1974; Gosling et al., 1987], lower than expected proton temperature (Tp/Tex &lt; 0.5)
[Gosling et al., 1973], enhanced alpha/proton ratio (Na/Np &gt; 0.08) [Borrini et al., 1982], enhanced magnetic field strength, low plasma beta (&lt; 0.1), and smooth rotation in the magnetic field vector [Burlaga et al., 1981]. The expected proton temperature (Tex) was calculated using the Tp – V relation from the Genesis mission [Neugebauer et al., 2003], which was derived from solar wind speed and
temperature measurements from both the Genesis spacecraft and the SWEPAM instrument [McComas et al., 1998b] on the Advanced Composition Explorer (ACE) spacecraft.

All ICME events were identified by eye using the signatures outlined above. In general, at least two signatures within a given solar wind interval were required before it was identified it as an ICME. It should be noted that owing to power limitations on the Ulysses spacecraft, the electron pitch angle distribution data used for identifying bi-directional electrons was unavailable from October 2004 through 25 March 2006 and available only intermittently after then.

The Ulysses ICME list presented here covers a period that coincides with the declining phase of solar cycle 22 and all of solar cycle 23.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1992-03-10T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2007-07-05T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListCaveats>Because of the nature of the Ulysses orbit, a nearly half (~49%) of these 178 events were observed at R &gt; 5.0 AU. The maximum number of events in a single year (39) occurred in 1999, coinciding with the
ascending phase of solar cycle 23, whereas only a single event was identified in the years 1995, 2006 and 2007. The latter were periods when Ulysses was embedded in the fast PCH flows, near solar minimum. Given that events were identified by eye, some smaller or less clear events may
have been excluded from our survey.</ListCaveats>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Need to add more to description.</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://swoops.lanl.gov/Ulysses-SWOOPSICMElist.doc#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>34</ListDBID>
<ListID>stereo_euvi_event</ListID>
<OldListID>stereo_euvi_catalog</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>STEREO/SECCHI/EUVI Event List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>STEREO/EUVI Event Catalog (&gt;C1 GOES class or &gt;12 keV RHESSI)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>This catalogue is a summary of the contents of the full STEREO/EUVI Event List at:

http://secchi.lmsal.com/EUVI/euvi_events.txt</ListDesc>
<ListStart>2006-12-04T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2009-07-08T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListRefURL>#http://secchi.lmsal.com/EUVI/euvi_catalog.txt#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>35</ListDBID>
<ListID>noaa_active_region_summary</ListID>
<OldListID>srs_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>NOAA/USAF Solar Active Region Summary List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>Parameters describing active regions: lat, long, size... (NOAA/USAF)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>  The Solar Region Summary (SRS), compiled by SWPC, is a daily report of   the active solar regions observed during the preceding day. The SRS   contains a detailed description of the active regions currently visible on the solar disk. See sample and description below.

  The characteristics for each active region are compiled from up to six observatories that report to the SWPC in near-real time. The sunspot counts are typically higher than those reported in non-real time by the Sunspot Index Data Center (SIDC), Brussels, Belgium, and the American Association of Variable Star Observers.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1996-01-02T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2011-01-18T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Index</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Need to complete the descriptions.</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#ftp://ftp.swpc.noaa.gov/pub/forecasts/SRS#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>36</ListDBID>
<ListID>noaa_daily_solar_data</ListID>
<OldListID>dsd_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>NOAA Daily Solar Data List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>Parameters describing solar activity: SSN, flare types...etc (NOAA)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The contents of this list is the Daily Solar Data prepared by the U.S. Dept. of Commerce, NOAA, Space Weather Prediction Center.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1994-01-01T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2011-01-17T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Index</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListCaveats>Missing data is shown as -1, except X-ray Background Flux is shown as *.</ListCaveats>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>This is an index so should be moved to context server or MDES (i.e. not an event)</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.swpc.noaa.gov/ftpdir/indices/old_indices/#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>37</ListDBID>
<ListID>soho_camp</ListID>
<OldListID>soho_camp</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>SOHO campaign</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of observing campaigns planned for SOHO Mission (SOHO/GSFC) .</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The contents of this list is a restructuring of the contents of the document: http://sohowww.nascom.nasa.gov/data/summary/asplanned/campaign/soho_campaign.dat                       in table format.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1996-03-06T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2010-05-07T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Event</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Get rid of this</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://sohowww.nascom.nasa.gov/data/summary/asplanned/campaign/soho_campaign.dat#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>38</ListDBID>
<ListID>sidc_sunspot_number</ListID>
<OldListID>sidc_sunspot_number</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>SIDC smoothed monthly sunspot no.</ListName>
<ListPurpose>Smoothed monthly sunspot number (SIDC, Belgium).</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The data are taken  from the Sunspot Index Data Centre data base at the Observatoire Royal de Belgique. An ASCII file which contains the monthly and monthly smoothed sunspot numbers since 1749 is updated by the SIDC on every 1st of the month. See  http://www.icsu-fags.org/ps11sidc.htm for more details.</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1749-07-01T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2010-06-30T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Index</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>This is an index so should be moved to context server or MDES (i.e. not an event)</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL> http://www.icsu-fags.org/ps11sidc.htm#http:// http://www.icsu-fags.org/ps11sidc.htm#</ListRefURL>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>39</ListDBID>
<ListID>drao_10cm_flux</ListID>
<OldListID>drao_10cm_flux</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>DRAO 10.7cm Radio Flux Monitor</ListName>
<ListPurpose>General index of solar activity (DRAO)</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>This index provides measurements of the 10.7cm Flux taken by DRAO. Each measurement is expressed in three values: the &quot;observed&quot;, &quot;adjusted&quot; and &quot;URSI Series D.&quot; values. 

The &quot;sfu_observed&quot; value is the number measured by the solar radio telescope. Since it is a measure of the emissions due to solar activity hitting the Earth, this is the quantity to use when terrestrial phenomena are being studied. This measurement is modulated by two quantities: the level of solar activity and the changing distance between the Earth and Sun.

The &quot;adjusted&quot; value is corrected for the annual modulation due to the changing distance between the Earth and Sun and is the quantity to use when solar phenomena are being studied.

Absolute measurements of flux density are quite difficult, and in the early years of solar radio astronomy, considerable effort around the world went into making absolute measurements of the solar flux density at a number of different frequencies. An attempt was then made to fit all these various data to a spectrum. Each set of measurements was then given a scaling factor that would move them right onto the fitted spectrum. For the 10.7cm Solar Flux a scaling factor of 0.9 was estimated. In the light of later work, this work should possibly be redone. However, we also give in the database the &quot;Series D Flux&quot;, which is the &quot;adjusted&quot; value multiplied by 0.9.

Three flux determinations are made each day. Between March and October measurements are made at 1700, 2000 (local noon) and 2300UT. However, the combination of location in a mountain valley and a relatively high latitude make it impossible to maintain these times during the rest of the year. Consequently, from November through February, the flux determination times are changed to 1800, 2000 and 2200, so that the Sun is high enough above the horizon for a good measurement to be made.

The record for each measurement of the 10.7cm Solar Flux is as below. The quantities are separated by commas. The 10.7cm Solar Flux is given in solar flux units (an sfu = 10^-22 W m^-2 Hz^-1)</ListDesc>
<ListStart>1975-01-01T00:00:00</ListStart>
<ListEnd>2007-06-06T00:00:00</ListEnd>
<ListType>Index</ListType>
<ListPriority>Primary</ListPriority>
<ListStatus>Active</ListStatus>
<ListProdNotes>Moves to MDES</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.spaceweather.gc.ca/sx-eng.php#</ListRefURL>
<ListAck>Dominion Radio Astrophysical Observatory (DRAO)</ListAck>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>40</ListDBID>
<ListID>cactus_soho_cme</ListID>
<OldListID>cactus_cme_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>CACTus SOHO/LASCO CME List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>This list contains parameters describing coronal mass ejections (CMEs) autonomously detected by CACTus in image sequences from SOHO/LASCO.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The CACTus software package (Computer Aided CME Tracking) was developed by the Solar Influences Data Center (SIDC) of the Royal Obervatory of Belgium; the project was co-funded by ESA (16913/03/NL/LvH).</ListDesc>
<ListCaveats>The CME list is automatically generated by CACTus; there is no human intervention or supervision at this stage. Caution should be used when employing the data for statistical purposes. See URLs http://www.sidc.be/cactus/ and http://secchi.nrl.navy.mil/cactus/
Some information (such as position angle) depends on the observatory location.</ListCaveats>
<ListProdNotes>This list has not yet been implemented but MSSL have the necessary conditioning code to convert the standard CACTUS output to something that can be ingested into the HEC

Modify field names to be consistent with other lists, pa_meas etc…</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.sidc.be/cactus/#</ListRefURL>
<ListAck>When any CACTus data are used please cite one of the following publications: 
http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2004A%26A...425.1097R
http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2009ApJ...691.1222R</ListAck>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>41</ListDBID>
<ListID>halo_cme_flare_magnetic_storm</ListID>
<OldListID>gopalswamy_cme_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>SOHO/LASCO Halo CME with assoc SGD H-alpha Flare and WDC Mag Storm List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>List of Halo CMEs and associated flares and geomagnetic storms.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>Three sets of information are listed: (i) halo coronal mass ejections (CMEs), (ii) Associated flares  and (iii) Associated geomagnetic storms. 

The halo CME list is obtained from the SOHO/LASCO CME catalog (http://cdaw.gsfc.nasa.gov/CME_list). The solar source location for each halo is obtained as the location of the associated H-alpha flare location if available from the online Solar Geophysical Data. Otherwise, the flare is identified by playing superposed LASCO and EIT movies along with GOES plots and deriving the heliographic coordinates of the associated flare from SOHO/EIT images. The minimum value of the Disturbance Storm Time (Dst) index is obtained from the World Data Center in Kyoto (http://swdcdb.kugi.kyoto-u.ac.jp/dstdir/). A 4-day long time window was chosen starting at CME onset+1 day and ending at CME onset + 5 days. The minimum value of Dst index in this time window after is halo CME is assigned to the halo CME.</ListDesc>
<ListProdNotes>This list has not yet been implemented. This is an outline of its contents to help with the refactoring of the HEC descriptions.</ListProdNotes>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>42</ListDBID>
<ListID>ulysses_grb_xray_flare</ListID>
<OldListID>ulyssess_grb_flare_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>Ulysses/GRB X-ray Flare List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>A list of solar X-ray events deteced by the Gamma Ray Burst (GMB) experiment on Ulysses</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>Abstract from Tranquille et al, Solar Phys (2009) 258:

Ulysses was launched in October 1990, and its Solar X-ray/Cosmic Gamma-Ray Burst Experiment (GRB) has provided more than 13 years of uninterrupted observations of solar X-ray flare activity. Due to the large variation of the relative solar latitude and longitude of the spacecraft orbit with respect to the Earth, the perspective of the GRB instrument often differed significantly from that of X-ray instruments on Earth-orbiting satellites. During extended periods the GRB experiment made direct observations of flares on the hidden face of the Sun, providing a unique record of events not visible to other instruments. The small detector area of GRB and its optimization for very high counting rates minimized the effects of pulse pile-up.We interpret the spectra, time histories, and occurrence distribution patterns of GRB data in terms of “thermal feed-through”, the confusion of thermal soft X-rays and non-thermal hard X-rays. This effect is a systematic problem for scintillation-counter spectrometers observing the solar hard X-ray spectrum. This paper provides a definitive catalog of the Ulysses X-ray flare observations and discusses various features of this unique database. For the equivalent GOES range X2 –X25, we find a power-law fit for the (differential) occurrence frequency at &gt;25 keV with slope −1.61 ± 0.04, with no evidence for a downturn at the highest event magnitudes (for the relatively small sample of such events available in this study). If the nine most intense events are excluded because of concerns about the effects of pulse pile-up, the slope steepens to −1.75±0.08.</ListDesc>
<ListProdNotes>This list has not yet been implemented and is included here to assist with refactoring of the HEC.

Need to check if this is a super set of all the lists or if need to also ingest other lists.

Also need to make sure parameter names are consistent.</ListProdNotes>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>43</ListDBID>
<ListID>cactus_stereoa_cme</ListID>
<OldListID>cactus_cme_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>CACTus STEREO-A/COR CME List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>This list contains parameters describing coronal mass ejections (CMEs) autonomously detected by CACTus in image sequences from STEREO-A/COR.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The CACTus software package (Computer Aided CME Tracking) was developed by the Solar Influences Data Center (SIDC) of the Royal Obervatory of Belgium; the project was co-funded by ESA (16913/03/NL/LvH).</ListDesc>
<ListCaveats>The CME list is automatically generated by CACTus; there is no human intervention or supervision at this stage. Caution should be used when employing the data for statistical purposes. See URLs http://www.sidc.be/cactus/ and http://secchi.nrl.navy.mil/cactus/</ListCaveats>
<ListProdNotes>This list has not yet been implemented but MSSL have the necessary conditioning code to convert the standard CACTUS output to something that can be ingested into the HEC

Modify field names to be consistent with other lists, pa_meas etc…</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.sidc.be/cactus/#</ListRefURL>
<ListAck>When any CACTus data are used please cite one of the following publications: 
http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2004A%26A...425.1097R
http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2009ApJ...691.1222R</ListAck>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>45</ListDBID>
<ListID>cactus_stereob_cme</ListID>
<OldListID>cactus_cme_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>CACTus STEREO-B/COR CME List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>This list contains parameters describing coronal mass ejections (CMEs) autonomously detected by CACTus in image sequences from STEREO-B/COR.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The CACTus software package (Computer Aided CME Tracking) was developed by the Solar Influences Data Center (SIDC) of the Royal Obervatory of Belgium; the project was co-funded by ESA (16913/03/NL/LvH).</ListDesc>
<ListCaveats>The CME list is automatically generated by CACTus; there is no human intervention or supervision at this stage. Caution should be used when employing the data for statistical purposes. See URLs http://www.sidc.be/cactus/ and http://secchi.nrl.navy.mil/cactus/</ListCaveats>
<ListProdNotes>This list has not yet been implemented but MSSL have the necessary conditioning code to convert the standard CACTUS output to something that can be ingested into the HEC

Modify field names to be consistent with other lists, pa_meas etc…</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.sidc.be/cactus/#</ListRefURL>
<ListAck>When any CACTus data are used please cite one of the following publications: 
http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2004A%26A...425.1097R
http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2009ApJ...691.1222R</ListAck>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>46</ListDBID>
<ListID>cactus_soho_flow</ListID>
<OldListID>cactus_cme_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>CACTus SOHO/LASCO Flow List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>This list contains parameters describing solar wind flows autonomously detected by CACTus in image sequences from SOHO/LASCO.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The CACTus software package (Computer Aided CME Tracking) was developed by the Solar Influences Data Center (SIDC) of the Royal Obervatory of Belgium; the project was co-funded by ESA (16913/03/NL/LvH).</ListDesc>
<ListCaveats>The CME list is automatically generated by CACTus; there is no human intervention or supervision at this stage. Caution should be used when employing the data for statistical purposes. See URLs http://www.sidc.be/cactus/ and http://secchi.nrl.navy.mil/cactus/</ListCaveats>
<ListProdNotes>This list has not yet been implemented but MSSL have the necessary conditioning code to convert the standard CACTUS output to something that can be ingested into the HEC

Modify field names to be consistent with other lists, pa_meas etc…</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.sidc.be/cactus/#</ListRefURL>
<ListAck>When any CACTus data are used please cite one of the following publications: 
http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2004A%26A...425.1097R
http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2009ApJ...691.1222R</ListAck>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>47</ListDBID>
<ListID>cactus_stereoa_flow</ListID>
<OldListID>cactus_cme_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>CACTus STEREO-A/COR Flow List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>This list contains parameters describing solar wind flows autonomously detected by CACTus in image sequences from STEREO-A/COR.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The CACTus software package (Computer Aided CME Tracking) was developed by the Solar Influences Data Center (SIDC) of the Royal Obervatory of Belgium; the project was co-funded by ESA (16913/03/NL/LvH).</ListDesc>
<ListCaveats>The CME list is automatically generated by CACTus; there is no human intervention or supervision at this stage. Caution should be used when employing the data for statistical purposes. See URLs http://www.sidc.be/cactus/ and http://secchi.nrl.navy.mil/cactus/</ListCaveats>
<ListProdNotes>This list has not yet been implemented but MSSL have the necessary conditioning code to convert the standard CACTUS output to something that can be ingested into the HEC

Modify field names to be consistent with other lists, pa_meas etc…</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.sidc.be/cactus/#</ListRefURL>
<ListAck>When any CACTus data are used please cite one of the following publications: 
http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2004A%26A...425.1097R
http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2009ApJ...691.1222R</ListAck>
</HEC_Lists>
<HEC_Lists>
<ListDBID>48</ListDBID>
<ListID>cactus_stereob_flow</ListID>
<OldListID>cactus_cme_list</OldListID>
<ListVersion>1.0</ListVersion>
<ListName>CACTus STEREO-B/COR Flow List</ListName>
<ListPurpose>This list contains parameters describing solar wind flows autonomously detected by CACTus in image sequences from STEREO-B/COR.</ListPurpose>
<ListDesc>The CACTus software package (Computer Aided CME Tracking) was developed by the Solar Influences Data Center (SIDC) of the Royal Obervatory of Belgium; the project was co-funded by ESA (16913/03/NL/LvH).</ListDesc>
<ListCaveats>The CME list is automatically generated by CACTus; there is no human intervention or supervision at this stage. Caution should be used when employing the data for statistical purposes. See URLs http://www.sidc.be/cactus/ and http://secchi.nrl.navy.mil/cactus/</ListCaveats>
<ListProdNotes>This list has not yet been implemented but MSSL have the necessary conditioning code to convert the standard CACTUS output to something that can be ingested into the HEC

Modify field names to be consistent with other lists, pa_meas etc…</ListProdNotes>
<ListRefURL>#http://www.sidc.be/cactus/#</ListRefURL>
<ListAck>When any CACTus data are used please cite one of the following publications: 
http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2004A%26A...425.1097R
http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2009ApJ...691.1222R</ListAck>
</HEC_Lists>
</dataroot>
